你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第八集
这里  我很喜欢
This place, I love it.
我就知道你会喜欢
I thought you might.
上次聊天时你提过想喝真正的意式咖啡
You mentioned craving some real espresso the last time we spoke.
从意大利回来后  我开始挑剔咖啡了
I think I became a coffee snob after living in Italy.
什么时候
When was that?
我大三是在威尼斯度过的
I spent my junior year in Venice.
美得像梦一样
It was like a beautiful daydream.
抱歉  这听起来挺傻
Sorry, that sounds silly.
不不  一点也不会
No, no, not at all.
我曾近距离观赏德・基里科的《红塔》
I got to be 2 feet away from De Chirico's the Red Tower.
他的作品总有一种
His paintings have that sense of...
神秘感  若隐若现
mystery, of something looming.
是啊  如同生命在那一刻静止
Yeah, it's like life is frozen in that moment
宇宙即将揭开所有的秘密
and the universe is about to reveal all its secrets.
是啊  而且从某种意义上说  确实
Yes, and it did, in a way.
那时起我就想当一名艺术家了
That's when I knew I wanted to be an artist.
你是啊
And here you are.
我  我只是个插图画家
Well... I-I'm just an illustrator.
我有时也画画
I mean, I paint sometimes,
但我要做的是去发掘
but what I do is about discovery.
每天  都有新的东西要学
Every day, there's a new lesson to learn,
有新的迷题待解
a new mystery around the corner.
那个  你去过意大利吗
So, uh, have you ever been to Italy?
我第一次是通过三维魔景机看到意大利乡村
I first saw the Italian countryside through a view-master.
那种播放循环幻灯片的影像机吗
The viewfinder thing with the circular slides?
是的
Exactly.
我连续看了几个小时
I spent hours looking through it,
假装我自己就在那里
pretending that I was actually there.
你亲自去看过吗
Did you ever get to see it in person?
大学之后  去了  而且
After college. Yeah, and...
那里甚至比我想像中还要美
it was even more beautiful than I had imagined.
值得等待
So it was worth the wait.
绝对值得
Unquestionably.
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  didina  二摆舞  紫玉  天朝直属
时间轴：擦擦  菜六水
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
通道  三角洲  第五元素  泽塔
Passage, Delta, Epsilon, Zeta,
胜利者  威士忌  运动  十一月  狐步舞
Victor, Whiskey, Motion, November, Foxtrot.
我吃过了  里瑟先生  谢谢
I've already eaten, Mr. Reese. Thank you.
谁说是给你的
Who said it was for you?
狗狗丹麦酥
Doggie Danish.
新号码是哪位啊
So who's our new number?
其实有两个号码
Two numbers, actually.
塞布丽娜・德雷克和丹尼尔・德雷克
Sabrina and Daniel Drake.
曼哈顿东村出版社的两位总裁
Co-CEOs of East Village Publishing.
德雷克一家身价一亿
The Drakes are worth over $100 million.
塞布丽娜・德雷克与其夫丹尼尔
Sabrina Drake met her husband Daniel
92年在兰顿出版社工作时相识
while working at Random House in '92.
位于纽约的著名出版社
两人随即辞职  私奔结婚
They both left their jobs shortly thereafter and eloped.
我还以为他们会在广场大酒店举办婚礼
I had 'em pegged for a wedding at The Plaza.
位于纽约的著名豪华酒店
也许她父母不想付婚礼费用
maybe her parents didn't want to pay for it.
美国风俗  由女方父母承担婚礼费用
德雷克先生出身穷寒
Mr. Drake grew up nearly destitute,
不过他很聪明
but he was smart,
弄到了西北大学的全额奖学金
and managed to finagle a full scholarship to Northwestern.
我看是有人想要他们的钱
I'd say someone's after their money.
或者为了复仇
Or revenge.
他们最近的出版物中公开强烈谴责
They recently released a scathing indictment
马里兰民兵组织  及其领导人韦德・哈金斯
of the Maryland Militia and its leader, Wade Huggins.
作者声称・哈金斯先生有超过一万支武器
The author claims that Mr. Huggins has more than 10,000 firearms
并教导其手下
and teaches his followers
制造汽车炸弹准备起义
to build car bombs in case of domestic insurgence.
哈金斯连发几次赤裸裸的威胁
Huggins has made a few thinly-veiled threats,
但没有确实举动
but has yet to make his move.
我想是机器看出
I imagine the machine has seen
他在计划某些事情
whatever it is he's planning on doing.
那你又有何计划呢  芬奇
And what are you planning, Finch?
你去德雷克的公司看看
I need you to go to the Drakes' place of business
我去他们家里
while I visit their home.
我真为你骄傲  芬奇
I'm proud of you, Finch.
你已经可以面不改色地
You've really gotten comfortable
擅闯民宅了
with your breaking and entering duties.
感谢阁下对鄙人越轨行为的赞赏
Thank you for appreciating my descent into deviant behavior.
说到公司
As for the workplace...
这是射频识别复制器
this is an rfid duplicator.
你只要扫描到智能卡  复制到这张空白卡上
You simply scan an active card, copy this blank,
就有权限进入所有公司办公室了
and you'll have access to all the company's offices.
那我从哪里找智能卡呢
And where do I get an active card?
我又不是服务全包  里瑟先生
I can't do everything, Mr. Reese.
快快快  我们要迟到了
Come on, come on, come on. We're going to be late.
除非提前20分钟也算迟到
Only if late means 20 minutes early.
我进来了  芬奇
I'm in, Finch.
到前台后  告诉他们你是来
When you reach reception, tell them you're there
参加哈罗德・克灵的会议
for the Harold Crane meeting.
我以投资新压印为名进行了预约
I made an appointment under the guise of investing in a new imprint.
我不会出现  而且很失礼地未曾取消
I'll be a no-show and rudely never call to cancel,
因此你应该有不少时间可以四处晃荡
which should buy you plenty of time to loiter.
那叫侦察  芬奇
It's called recon, Finch.
放松  你一紧张我就会跟着紧张
Relax. You're anxiety is giving me anxiety.
我知道  抱歉  不过你也知道他
I know, I'm sorry, but you know how he is.
他总是第一个到
He always has to be the first to arrive.
亨利拿我们总是迟到当话柄
Henry takes this irritated pleasure with us always being late,
丹尼尔・德雷克
强制配对
即使我们早到
even if we're early.
可笑的高压攻势
It's an absurd power play.
马蒂又从大西洋月刊打来电话了
Marty called from The Atlantic, again.
想知道我们对《十佳》那篇文章的看法
He wanted to know your thoughts on the "Ten Be" article.
那家伙真固执
That guy is persistent.
告诉他我明天回他电话
Tell him I'll call him tomorrow
提醒我今天回家前读完那篇文章
and make sure I read that before I go home today.
您来见哪位  先生
Who are you here to see, Sir?
我在等我的老板  哈罗德・克灵
Yes, I'm waiting on my employer, Harold Crane.
好的
Okay.
没问题  他到后请告诉我
Yes, of course. Please tell me when he arrives.
这公司不卖  亨利
This company is not for sale, Henry.
没有不卖的公司
Every company is for sale.
他们出价已经两周了
The offer's been on the table for two weeks.
-他们不会永远等下去的  -那就走吧
- They're not gonna wait forever. - So let 'em walk.
律师审过几十次了  很可靠
Legal went over this proposal dozens of times, it's solid.
数字会说话
The numbers speak for themselves.
如果失去对产品的控制  数字什么也说明不了
The numbers mean nothing if we don't have control over our product.
我们本季度下滑了20%  上季度是15%
We were down 20% this quarter, 15% in the last.
恕我直言  我可不认为
With all due respect, I'm not sure
创意控制是我们的当务之急
creative control is what we need right now.
我们不是唯一一家
We're not the only publishing house
有困难的出版社  亨利
who's having troubles, Henry.
兰顿出版社可没怎么发牢骚
Random House doesn't seem to be complaining.
得了  他们的规模是我们的三倍
Oh, come on, they're three times our size.
你想任五亿巨资与你擦身而过吗  丹尼尔
You want to walk away from $1/2 billion, Daniel?
明天开董事会  让他们投票  然后再决定
The board meets tomorrow. I say we let 'em vote, then we decide.
投票  你和塞布丽娜是大股东
A vote? You and Sabrina are majority shareholders.
你们俩的票才是关键  你们心里清楚
Your votes are the only ones that matter, and you know it.
你听到了吗
You're hearing this?
看来是有分歧啊  芬奇
There seems to be some discontent in the ranks, Finch.
有人出价要买公司
Someone made an offer on the company,
那迫不及待的  名叫享利
and there's a very eager taker. His name's Henry.
享利・布鲁克斯
Henry Brooks.
他是德雷克的第一个投资者
He was the Drake's first investor,
现在仍拥有公司5%的股份
and still owns 5% of the company.
这么说如果收购黄了  他损失不少
Which means he has a lot to lose if that deal doesn't go through.
你们经理打电话来说你要重约时间
Your manager called and said you had to reschedule.
说是什么电脑故障
Something about a computer malfunction.
那是误会
It's a misunderstanding.
好的  德雷克先生及其夫人要求
Good, because Mr. and Mrs. Drake have requested
为整个屋子都装上高速光纤
high-speed fiber optic throughout the house.
没问题
That won't be a problem.
里瑟先生  德雷克家里快搞定了
Mr. Reese, I'm almost finished at the Drakes'.
很温馨的家
It's quite a lovely home.
也别太"面不改色"了  芬奇
Don't get too comfortable, Finch.
塞布丽娜正要去城市的另一边开会
Sabrina's on her way to a meeting across town,
她丈夫在76街公园附近有个午餐会
and the husband has a lunch meeting near 76th and park.
我可没有分身术
I can't keep eyes on both of 'em.
餐厅在石街区附近
The restaurant is close to the Brownstone.
我盯着他  你去跟德雷克夫人
I'll keep an eye on him while you follow Mrs. Drake.
是的  没错  六点见
Yeah, that's right. Meet me at 6:00,
12街格林威治拐角处
corner of 12th and Greenwich
来电
未知号码
对对  我还在
Yeah, yeah, I'm still here.
卡特
Carter.
弗斯科都第二次把我转去语言信箱了
That's the second time Fusco sent me to voice mail.
我是不是该生气了
Should I be offended?
我是我搭档的保姆吗  约翰
Am I my partner's keeper, John?
不是  不过我肯定你对此略有见解
No, but I'll bet you still have an opinion.
我想给他做无罪推定
I want to give him the benefit of the doubt,
不过这家伙神神叨叨的
but guy's been acting jumpy.
鬼鬼祟祟地接电话
Sneaking off, taking phone calls,
像是有事儿
that sort of thing.
我会去查  不过首先
I'll look into it, but first,
你尽量查个人
you need to find out anything you can
他名叫韦德・哈金斯
about a man named Wade Huggins.
马里兰民兵组织的韦德・哈金斯
Maryland Militia Wade Huggins?
我刚接到消息他要来城里
I just got a heads up he's on his way to town
去一家出版公司进行抗议
to protest a publishing company.
我需要他的位置
I need his location.
看来你知道什么我不知道的
I take it you know something that I don't.
出版社的所有人夫妇有麻烦了
The husband and wife owners are in trouble.
我正在查是什么引起的
I'm just trying to find out who's causing it.
里瑟先生  丹尼尔・德雷克现在离开餐厅了
Mr. Reese, Daniel Drake is leaving the restaurant now.
芬奇  你还在盯着那位丈夫吗
Finch, do you still have eyes on the husband?
是的  怎么了
Yes. What's the matter?
有没有发现什么可疑情况或异常情况
Do you see anything suspicious or out of place?
没有  里瑟先生
No, Mr. Reese.
德里克夫人出事了吗
Has something happened to Mrs. Drake?
有人往她车里装了东西
A man just planted something on her car.
什么东西  是追踪装置吗
What kind of something? Like a tracking device?
除非追踪装置带有遥控雷管
Not unless tracking devices come with remote detonators.
炸弹  德里克夫人呢
A bomb. Where's Mrs. Drake?
我在她到前取了下来
I got to it before she arrived.
谢天谢地  你怎么做的
Thank God. What'd you do with it?
还没做
Nothing yet.
我们应该叫拆弹小组吧
Shouldn't we call the bomb squad?
没时间了  有来电触发装置
No time. It's got a cell phone trigger.
随时可能有来电
Call might come in at any second.
约翰  扔掉它快跑
John, you need to get away from it right now.
只要  找对线
Just need... to get to the wires.
约翰  你在吗
John, are you there?
我没事  芬奇
I'm okay, Finch.
装置是自制的
The device was homemade.
很粗糙  不过足以完成任务
Crude, but it would have gotten the job done.
现在我们有了炸弹客的手机号码
Now, we have a contact number for our bomber.
喂
Yeah?
我无意忽视你的濒死经历  里瑟先生
I don't mean to minimize your near death experience, Mr. Reese,
不过你确定自己黑入
but are you certain that you bluejacked
丹尼尔・德里克的手机了吗
Daniel Drake's phone?
今早  电梯里  怎么了
This morning, on the elevator. Why?
他还有一个手机
He must have a second one.
强制配对
完成
你说已经搞定了  圣地
You said it was handled, Santi.
放松  我在搞了
Relax, I'm on it.
最好是  否则
Well, you better be. Otherwise,
我不会给你余款的  明白吗
I'm gonna keep the rest of your fee, you got it?
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese,
我们要费心的不是马里兰民兵组织
It's not the Maryland Militia we need to worry about.
炸弹客刚刚联系了丹尼尔・德里克
The bomber just contacted Daniel Drake.
看来下令杀他妻子的人就是他
It seems he's the one that tried to kill his wife.
芬奇  德里克夫妇回办公室了
Finch, the Drakes are back at their office.
多谢你今天早上的诸多支持
Thank you for your support this morning.
不用担心
Oh, don't worry,
你已经清楚表明了你对这件事的看法
you made it really clear how you feel about the matter.
需要人执手安慰就去找你的心理医生  塞布丽娜
call your shrink if you need someone to hold your hand, Sabrina.
我真不敢相信你居然要卖掉
I can't believe you want to sell
我们唯一的成果
the only thing we ever did right.
知道吗  我一直清楚你是个失败主义者
You know what, I always knew you were defeatist.
却不知道你是个没骨气的
I never knew you were spineless.
如果"没骨气"是指"财政审慎"  我认
If by "spineless" you mean "fiscally prudent", fine.
不是每个人都含着金汤匙长大
Not all of us grew up with nannies and Tiffany rattles.
又开始大谈"苦出身"了  你最爱来这套
Oh, the poor-kid card. That's your favorite.
你这个固执的  冥顽的
You are a stubborn, obtuse,
放纵的伪知识分子
overindulged pseudo-intellectual.
是吗  抱歉噢  那我们俩是谁上过耶鲁大学
Really? I'm sorry. Which one of us went to Yale?
-又开始了  是啊好吧  -是我
- Oh, there we go. Yeah, okay. - 'Cause that would be me.
你上哪里来着  西北大学
And where did you go? Northwestern.
-你保底的学校  -我保底的学校
- Oh, your safety school. - My safety school.
知道吗  你就只管随心所欲吧  亲
You know what? Keep trying to deflect all you want, hon,
但有脑子的女人会看到墙上高挂一行字
but a smart girl like you should see the writing on the wall:
"是时候卖掉公司了"
It is time to sell the company.
绝对不
Absolutely not.
你永远不会承认自己有错的  是吧
You know, you can't admit being wrong in anything, can you?
你永远不会放手  错了也不放
You can never admit to losing anything, no matter how misguided.
你听到了吗  芬奇
Are you hearing this, Finch?
显然我们低估了他们的婚姻分歧
Apparently we underestimated their marital discontent.
简直是互憎互厌
Sounds more like disgust.
你拆掉的那个引爆装置
The components of the incendiary device that you defused
正好跟民兵组织
are an exact replica of one
秘密手册里所记载的一款相同
detailed in the Militia's Underground Manual.
这么说丹尼尔・德里克雇人造了个炸弹
So Daniel Drake hired someone to build a bomb
这炸弹可以轻易追溯到
that could be easily traced to a group
那个曾公开威胁他们的组织上
that had publicly threatened their lives.
聪明
Very clever.
看来谋杀也是解除婚姻的方式之一
Guess murder is one way to break up a marriage.
不过离婚不是更简单吗
but wouldn't divorce have been simpler?
如果他想出售成功则不然了
Not if he wants the sale to go through.
弗兰克・迈考特想卖掉[洛杉矶]道奇队时
When Frank Mccourt was trying to sell The Dodgers,
被他那起
it was held up for months while he went through
史上最昂贵的离婚耽搁了数月
one of the most expensive divorce cases in history.
我不知道你还是棒球迷呢  芬奇
I didn't know you were a baseball fan, Finch.
-[纽约]大都会队  -不见得
- The Mets? - Not particularly.
-[巴尔的摩]金莺队  -也许吧
- Orioles? - I suppose.
-[奥克兰]运动家队  -奥克兰不错
- The A's. - Oakland is fine,
还有[芝加哥]小熊队  [波士顿]红袜队
and The Cubs, and the Red Sox too.
不过  我不确定我对某支球队的偏爱
Although, I'm not certain my affection for any one of these teams
会暴露我在何处长大  里瑟先生
would reveal where I grew up, Mr. Reese.
好吧  现在情况如何
Okay, where were we?
我在他们家里发现了两人的遗嘱
I found both the Drakes' wills on their home computer.
如果德雷克夫人死亡
In the event of her death,
她的股票会转至其丈夫名下
Mrs. Drake's shares go to her husband.
24小时内他肯定会再次试图谋杀她的
So he will no doubt try to kill her again in the next 24 hours.
我们得找到那个杀手
We need to find that hit man.
德雷克说的那个名字查的怎样了  圣地
What about the name Drake used?  "Santi"?
我猜应该是
My best guess is that
一个叫内斯特・圣地亚哥的人
it belongs to a man named Nestor Santiago.
他多次出现在德雷克先生的通话记录
He's listed a number of times on Mr. Drake's phone records.
他们在弗布什的同一条街长大的
They grew up on the same street in Flatbush.
-儿时玩伴  -有现在的住址吗
- Childhood friends. - We have a recent address?
圣地亚哥八个月前刚从辛辛监狱放出来
Mr. Santiago was in Sing Sing until eight months ago.
之后就未出现在官方文件中了
Since then, he's stayed off the government's radar.
不过  逮捕他的警探之一
Although, one of the arresting detectives
就在第八区工作
works at the Eighth Precinct.
我已经请卡特警探帮忙了
I've enlisted Detective Carter's help.
我记得圣地亚哥  这白痴干什么了
Yeah, I remember Santiago. What'd that idiot do now?
他可能涉及一起谋杀
He may be involved in a homicide.
有什么办法让我们找到他吗
Anything you can do to shed some light on his whereabouts?
不太容易  他是个小毒贩
Not offhand. He was a small-time dealer,
后来开始吸食自己的货
started using his own product,
沉迷其中  不能自拔
and took a dive down the rabbit hole.
我在曼哈顿西部抓到他在贩毒
I pinched him selling in Hell's Kitchen.
没穿鞋  没穿上衣  腰里别着点四五手枪
No shoes, no shirt, and a .45 tucked into his jockeys.
他怎么这么快就出来了
How'd he get off with so little time?
律师好啊  某个上东区的金装律师
Good lawyer. Some overpriced suit from the upper east.
圣地亚哥干了什么
What did Santiago do?
我不能跟你说  比彻
I can't read you in on this one, Beecher.
好吧  我明白这套
Yeah, I know the drill.
凶案组是最高级的
Homicide task force is first class,
我们就是帮忙的
and the rest of us are coach.
不是那样的
It's not like that.
我就随嘴一说罢了  卡特
I'm just busting your balls, Carter.
让凶案组的人欠我个人情总是好的
It's always good to have one of you Task Forcers owe me a favor,
尤其此人还散发着玫瑰芬芳而不是满身烟味
especially one who smells like rose petals instead of an ashtray.
谢谢  是茉莉
Thanks, it's jasmine.
我的一个线人正和
Hey, listen, one of my undercovers is working with
与他合作过的毒贩一起干
a dealer who used to do business with him.
我去看看有什么线索
Let me see what I can dig up.
我绝对欠你一次
I will definitely owe you one.
芬奇  德雷克夫妇动身了
Finch, the Drakes are on the move.
他们前去参加公司
They're heading to a book signing
一名签约作家的签售会
for one of their authors.
我非常支持温室气体减排
I'm all for cutting greenhouse gases,
不过你应该还记得德雷克先生
but you do remember that Mr. Drake
想杀了他妻子吧
is trying to kill his wife?
她丈夫不是那种会脏自己手的人
The husband isn't the type to get his hands dirty.
我确信他不会在配有司机的
I'm confident he won't kill his wife
"林肯城市"后座上杀了他妻子
in the back of their chauffeured Town Car.
明白  不过我可不敢保证
Understood, but I wouldn't put it past him
他不会在活动上动什么手脚
to pull something at the event,
民兵组织的人也会在那儿
and the militia members will be in attendance.
正是栽赃的好时机
Perfect timing for a frame job.
芬奇  六点钟方向发现狙击手
Finch, I got a sniper on my 6:00.
我去救那妻子
I got the wife.
我不确定狙击手的目标是德雷克夫人  里瑟先生
I'm not sure it's Mrs. Drake the sniper's after, Mr. Reese.
她刚给一个匿名号码发了个短信
She just sent a text to an anonymized number.
内容是"现在"
It just says, "Now".
丈夫才是目标
The husband is the target.
看着点
Excuse you.
没事  有个疯子  他刚
No, just some maniac. He just
里瑟先生  怎么回事
Mr. Reese? What's happening?
马里兰民兵保卫美国
Maryland Militia protects America!
你们发表的是谎言
You're publishing lies!
马里兰民兵保卫美国
Maryland Militia protects America!
曼哈顿东村出版社不知羞耻
Shame on East Village Publishing!
德雷克夫人又发了一条短信
Mrs. Drake just sent another text.
只有一串问号和感叹号
It's several question marks and exclamation points.
芬奇  我明白
Finch, I think I've figured out
为什么机器吐出两个号码了
why the machine gave us both numbers.
德雷克夫妇想要干掉彼此
The drakes took out a hit on each her.
不好意思来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
离开办公室前手头又有活儿了
I had a few things to finish up before I left the office.
有什么要告诉我的吗  哈罗德
Something you want to share, Harold?
自从你论文答辩后我还没见你如此紧张过
I haven't seen you this nervous since your thesis presentation.
方帕不错嘛
Nice pocket square.
怎么  激情约会啊
What, do you have a hot date?
你个老东西  她是谁
You old dog. What's her story?
别这样  没什么  奈森
Stop. It's nothing, Nathan.
当然  讨论你的恋爱经历
Of course. Talking about your love life
有违你的隐形人风范
would run at cross purposes with your invisible man routine.
没事  哈罗德  我明白
That's okay, Harold, I get it.
不过记住
Just remember,
秘密对一段关系的影响深远
while mystery is a powerful tool in a relationship...
慢慢会积小成大
a little goes a long way.
相信我
Trust me.
昨天是你朋友的婚礼
Your friend's wedding was yesterday.
我猜你见到奥莉薇亚了
I take it you saw Olivia?
是的  见到了
Yeah, I did.
调停后我就没见过奥莉薇亚了
I hadn't seen Olivia since the mediation.
你和她说话了吗
Did you speak with her?
我试了
I tried.
你知道比恨更狠的是什么吗
You know the only thing worse than hate?
形同陌路
Indifference.
这些年我对她说了太多的谎
I told her so many lies over the years,
有一半我都不记得是什么了
I don't even remember what half of them were.
真相总会浮出水面的  哈罗德
The truth always catches up to you, Harold,
无论你如何隐瞒
no matter how hard you try and hide it.
这么说两名受害人同样也是行凶者
So we have two victims who are also perpetrators,
别提还有两名杀手
not to mention two hit men.
里瑟先生  我有考虑过
You know, Mr. Reese, it did occur to me,
我们可以让德雷克夫妇自生自灭
we could leave the Drakes to their own devices.
这有点势利啊  芬奇
That's pretty mercenary of you, Finch.
我喜欢
I kind of like it.
这样的话  我似乎跨越道德底线了
If that's the case, I may have crossed some moral threshold.
我不禁在想
I can't help thinking about
还有无辜的人需要我们的帮助
the innocent people who could use our help
而我们却在浪费时间帮助一对
while we're spending all our time with a couple
不去做婚姻咨询却相互残杀的夫妻
that have chosen murder over marriage counseling.
我们有其他号码吗
Well, do we have another number?
很遗憾  没有
Sadly, no.
那今天就是德雷克夫妇的幸运日了
Then it's the Drakes' lucky day,
不过我们还是需要调用帮手
but we're going to need all hands on deck.
你能找到弗斯科吗
Were you able to locate Fusco?
先是把我转去了语音信箱
After sending my messages to voice mail,
然后弗斯科警探就把手机电池拔了
Detective Fusco removed his cell phone battery.
卡特说对了  他正在谋划什么
Carter was right. He's up to something.
他最后一次使用手机是在
Last time he used his cell phone
12街和格林尼治街交口
was at 12th street and Greenwich avenue.
我们最好查查他卷进什么事了
We better find out what he's got himself mixed up in.
有什么问题吗  莱奈尔
Is something wrong, Lionel?
没  我很好
No, I'm--I'm fine.
抱歉订了这么早的桌
Sorry about the early reservation.
要不就得订十点半的了  所以我就
The only other one they had was 10:30, so I figured--
没事  我喜欢只有我们俩
It's okay, I like that we got it all to ourselves.
很漂亮啊  你看
That is so pretty. Look at it.
是啊  我  这个
Yeah. I am. It's, uh...
很小
small.
拉里真好  撮合我们两个
It was nice of Larry to set us up, right?
他人很好
He's a sweetie.
是啊  我们的孩子在一起打曲棍球
Yeah, our kids play hockey together.
他的儿子米切尔是我的学生
His son Mitchell is one of my students.
很难抽时间陪儿子吧
Must be hard to spend much time with your son.
我是说  你身为一名警探
I mean, being a detective and all.
工作时间很长吧
Those are long hours, right?
我前妻是这么认为的
Eh, my ex thought so.
不过这工作倒也没什么意思
But the job's not that interesting anyway.
我觉得挺有意思啊
I think it's super interesting.
相信我  你会觉得很无聊
Believe me, you'd be bored.
打扰了  先生  有您的电话
Excuse me, Sir, there's a phone call for you.
抱歉  我要接一下
Sorry, I got to take that.
我这儿正有事呢
Hey, I'm kind of in the middle of something here.
如果服务生所言可信
If I could believe the waiter,
你的事快玩完了
it sounds like you're near the end of something.
你真的应该提高一下谈话技巧
You really do need to work on your conversational skills.
这次要救谁吧
So who needs saving?
我需要你监视叫塞布丽娜・德雷克的女人
I need you to keep an eye on a woman named Sabrina Drake.
我现在给你发地址  另外  拜托
I'm sending you the address, and, please,
把你的手机电池放回该放的地方
put your cell phone battery back where it belongs.
抱歉  是工作
I'm sorry, that was work.
我得去盯梢了
I just got called in to a stakeout.
好
Okay.
要是你不想改天再约  我可以理解
I understand if you don't want to take a rain check on the date.
我的工作经常如此
I mean, my job gets in the way a lot.
我理解  莱奈尔  我表兄是警察
I understand, Lionel. My cousin's a cop.
工资低  工时长
Bad pay. Bad hours.
要不我陪你吧
What if I join you?
我们不搞这种美食试吃了
We could give up on our foodie experiment
去我最喜欢的沙拉三明治店
and go to my favorite falafel place.
真的
Yeah?
德雷克先生有没有做什么不该做的
Mr. Drake doing anything he shouldn't?
正常工作  就像一切如常
Oh, he's working like everything's normal...
就像他没找旧友杀他妻子
and he didn't hire an ex-con to kill his wife.
是啊  弗斯科说他太太也在努力工作
Yeah. Fusco says the missus is hard at work too.
两个人到底是如何从相爱
How did two people go from being in love
变成相杀呢
to wanting each other dead?
相爱是一回事
Being in love is one thing.
结婚  又是另一回事了
Being married, a whole different animal.
婚礼誓言改变了一切
Those vows change everything.
哪一句  "直到死亡将我们分开"
Which one? "Till death do us part."
是啊  差不多吧
Yeah, something like that.
有一天你嫁给了自己的灵魂伴侣
One day you're married to your soul mate,
然后眼睁睁看着他们变成了另一个人
then you watch them turn into someone else.
有时  你太爱这人曾经的样子
Sometimes you're so in love with who a person was,
无能再爱上他们改变后的样子
you can't bring yourself to love who they've become.
你想过开始新生活吗
You ever think about moving on?
约会吗
Like dating?
当然
Sure.
等我有空了  比如我不再是单亲妈妈
In my spare time, like when I'm not being a single mom
不再是凶案组警探  不再干这些事
or a homicide detective, or whatever this is.
你呢
What about you?
稍等
One second.
-卡特  -我是比彻
- Carter. - Hey, it's Beecher.
圣地亚哥有新消息吗
You got any news on Santiago?
是的  我问了我的人  他说圣地亚哥
Yeah, I talked to my guy. He said Santiago was
四处打听哪能偷到送餐的货车
asking around about where to boost a deli-to-door van.
说他要用来进入中城区某出版社大楼
Said he needed it to access some publishing building in midtown.
多谢  比彻
Thanks, Beecher.
我看圣地亚哥正要去找德雷克夫人
I think Santiago is on his way to see Mrs. Drake.
有人切断了电源
Someone cut the power.
看来德雷克夫人的杀手找到目标了
Looks like Mrs. Drake's hit man just found his target.
这傻帽抢劫完
So this dumbass forgets to log out
忘了退出他的脸书账户
of his Facebook account after he robs the place.
我们两小时之后抓住了他  猜他在干嘛
We pick him up two hours later. Guess what he's doing.
更新状态
Updating his status?
他难以自控啊
He couldn't help himself.
我真高兴你能来  朗达
I'm so glad you came, Rhonda.
我也是
Me too.
怎么了
What?
警探  我们有状况了
Detective, we have a problem.
送货员刚刚到了29层
Delivery man just arrived on the 29th floor.
好  我这就过去
All right, I'm on my way.
我很快回来  好吗
Look, I'll be right back, okay?
-好  -好的
- Okay. - All right.
纽约警察
NYPD!
谁在我的地盘
Who the hell is on my property?
-蹲下  -这些人干嘛
- Get down! - What are those guys--
蹲下
Get down!
追  追
Go! Go!
你们是什么人  到底怎么回事
Who are you people? What is going on?
谁快点告诉我
Somebody better talk to me right now
到底怎么回事
and tell me what the heck is going on!
我要
I want--
你干嘛
What are you doing?
俗话说"舍不得老婆抓不住流氓"啊
Sometimes you need to break a few eggs to save lives.
我确定"俗话"不是那么说的
Yeah, pretty sure that's not the saying.
兄弟
Hey, pal.
要我帮忙么
Can I help you?
不管你的事  小子
None of your business, bruja.
是警探小子  你有证件吗
It's detective bruja. You got some ID?
怎么了
What's happening?
纽约警察  没事的  夫人
NYPD. Everything's okay, ma'am.
好了  请跟我来
All right, come with me.
快快快快
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
你的支援呢  不应该有支援吗
Where's your backup? Shouldn't there be backup?
他们到了
Here they are now.
你看上去不像警官
You don't look like a police officer.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
放我下来  放我下来
Put me down! Put me down!
救命  救命  来人啊
Help! Help! Somebody help!
-救命  -有这个必要吗
- Help! - Is that really necessary?
现在不制止
If we don't stop this now,
他们的争斗就会伤及无辜
innocent people will get caught in their marital crossfire,
我不允许
and I won't let that happen.
干得好  莱奈尔
Good job, Lionel.
没事  哥一直渴望协同绑架
Yeah, always wanted to be accessory to kidnapping.
多重绑架
Multiple kidnappings.
好在这是非工作时间  因为
It's a good thing it's after hours, because--
莱奈尔  你说得对
Lionel, you were right.
拐角的确有家冰冻酸奶店
There was a fro-yo place right around the corner.
这些是你同事吗
These your co-workers?
-我是卡特  -朗达  很高兴认识你
- Hi, I'm Carter. - Rhonda. Nice to meet you.
我正在跟弗斯科汇报进展
Yeah, I was just catching Fusco up on a case,
你既然已经了解了  我就撤了  好吧
and now you're all up to speed, I'm gonna leave, okay?
好  可以了
Yup, okay, you're good!
告诉我们你要多少  我们都给
Just tell us what you want. We will pay you.
不管你要什么  我们都给
We will pay you handsomely, whatever you want.
-你知道我们是什么人吗  -相信我
- Do you know who we are? - Trust me on this.
我们认识人能让你永世不得翻身
We know people who will put you away for the rest of your life.
闭嘴  塞布丽娜
Shut up, Sabrina.
你没条件跟疯子谈判
You are in no position to negotiate with this maniac.
至少我在维护自己的尊严
Well, at least I'm standing up for myself.
至于你  不如直接请他喝一杯卡布奇诺
You, on the other hand, might as well offer him a cappuccino!
真是太抱歉了我就想要
Well, forgive me because I want to leave here
四肢俱全地离开这儿  就是
with all my body parts intact. That's--oh.
求你拿开吧  我们很抱歉
Please take these off. We're sorry.
我们不想惹麻烦
We don't want any trouble.
-有点晚了  -无论  无论你要什么
- Little late for that. - Whatev--whatever you want,
只要开口  我们都可以给你
just tell us, we will make it happen.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是阻止你们两个小丑自相残杀的人
I'm the guy who stopped you two jokers from killing each other.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
内斯特・圣地亚哥在哪儿
Where's Nestor Santiago?
内斯特
Nestor?
你雇了内斯特来杀我  那个吸毒成性的疯子
You hired Nestor to kill me? The drug-addicted lunatic?
至于你  找了质高价优的专业人士
You, on the other hand, went upscale, professional.
你有联系电话或者地址吗
Do you have a contact number or an address?
你太自私了
You are so selfish.
我自私
I'm the one who's selfish.
那上一次你热心助人是几时来着
When's the last time you did anything for someone other than yourself?
居然还有脸说这话
Oh, says the good Samaritan.
你知道吗  你不在办公室
Do you know, when you're not in the office,
就满嘴的厨房挡板啊  颜色调板啊
all you talk about are backsplashes and color palettes?
我问你的意见  是因为我想知道你的意见
I ask your opinion because I want your opinion.
至于你  却一直在无视我
You, on the other hand, ignore me.
我不在乎
I don't care!
一个人能把厨房装修几次
How many times can a person redo their kitchen?
我喜欢你折腾三遍之前的那个厨房
I liked the one we had three kitchens ago.
那是你甘于平庸
If you're okay with mediocrity.
这是干嘛
What is this?
婚姻咨询
Marriage counseling.
为什么不直接把他们吊在天花板上
Why not just dangle them off the roof
逼他们说出如何找到杀手
and force them to tell us how to find the hit men?
约翰大概会喜欢这一选择
While John would probably enjoy that option,
那只能治标不治本
it would be a temporary solution.
我们得确保德雷克夫妇
We need to make sure the Drakes
不会再企图谋杀对方
won't try to kill each other again.
也该试试别的方法了
Maybe it's time to try a different tack.
我到了
This is me.
今天挺有趣的哈
That was fun, huh?
我的第一次盯梢
My first stakeout.
也许下次我还能看见行动呢
Maybe next time I'll even see some action.
下次
Next time?
好
Okay.
谁在那儿
Who's there?
-求你了  我们想回家  -怎么了
- Please, we'd like to go home. - What's going on?
如果你回家  圣地亚哥先生就会找到你
If you go home, Mr. Santiago will find you,
而你雇的杀手  德雷克夫人
and your hit man, Mrs. Drake,
对你丈夫也做同样打算
will likely have the same plan for finding your husband.
你是谁  你为什么要这么做
Who are you, and why are you doing this?
我们助人为乐
We help people,
即使他们不值得我们助
even when they don't necessarily deserve it.
你一定觉得我们是恶棍
You must think we're monsters.
不  我曾看到过真正的恶棍  德雷克夫人
No. I have looked into the faces of real monsters, Mrs. Drake.
我现在看到的是两个人
What I see here are two people
因为彼此不再交流
who stopped talking to one another,
相互怨恨  反目成仇
whose frustration turned to hatred.
然而  不像别的夫妻
Although, unlike other couples,
你们选择了谋杀对方  而不是离婚
you've opted for murder instead of divorce.
我想我该赞赏你们如此目标明确
I suppose I should commend you for being so goal-oriented.
不不  你们看上去不像恶棍
No, no, you don't look like monsters.
事实上  你们看上去曾非常相爱
In fact, you used to look like you were very much in love.
-您是格蕾斯吗  -什么
- Are you Grace? - Excuse me?
我是  谢谢你
Yes. Hi. Thank you.
欢迎参加  你的生日寻宝
第一站  90和第5大街路口
巧克力酥皮是我的最爱
Chocolate-covered's my favorite.
他给你留了东西
He left you something else.
能帮我拿一下吗  谢谢
Can you hold that? Thank you.
下一站
克莱曼婷花店
麦迪逊大街72号
晚上11点
放心去找弗兰克
那是在我叔叔的海滨别墅
That's my uncle's beach house.
是啊  还有你婶婶恐怖的纯素沙拉
Yeah, and your aunt's awful vegan smoothies.
吃起来像发霉的花生
They tasted like rotten peanuts.
你拼命想离开
You were desperate to leave,
说你要去游泳
and said you wanted to go swimming.
那是我们几周来的第一天假
It was our first day off in weeks.
是的  但是我们忘带泳衣了
Right, but we forgot our bathing suits.
我想全裸释放
I wanted to go au naturale,
但是你担心那些孩子
but you were worried about those kids.
我可不想你因为
I didn't want you to be arrested for
在海难的未成年人面前裸奔而被捕
running around bare-ass naked in front of a bunch of minors.
你那时还怀着孕
You were still pregnant then.
我不太了解我雇佣的人
I don't know much about the man I hired,
但是我知道的全告诉你
but I'll tell you what I can.
我通过一家私人保安公司联系了一个人
I contacted somebody through a private security firm.
我汇了一半的钱给了一个瑞士银行的账户
I wired half the money to a Swiss Bank account
然后得到了一个电话号码
and got a phone number in return,
剩下的钱完事后再付
and the rest was due after.
我想过叫停  但是那个号码
I tried to call it off, but the number
签售会以后就停用了
stopped working after the book signing.
那圣地亚哥呢
And Santiago?
我昨天联系过他  告诉他我改主意了
I tried to call him yesterday, tell him I changed my mind,
但是
but...
他一直恨你  亲爱的
he always hated you, honey.
他说就当是帮我忙了
Yeah, he said I should consider it a favor.
我们要去哪儿
Where are we going?
你说你想回家  那就回吧
You said you want to go home. That's where we're going.
你  你说过他们会在那儿等我们
You--you said they'd be expecting us there.
叫不回杀手  只好引杀手来找我们
If we can't call off the dogs, we'll bring them to us.
来吧
Come on.
你好
Hello.
你也好
Hello back.
谢谢你安排的寻宝
Thank you so much for the scavenger hunt.
我太喜欢了
I loved it.
上来吧
Come on up.
你怎么能安排这些
How did you get us in here?
我是讲解员
I work as a docent.
时不时能有点额外的好处
It affords me a few perks now and then.
今天真谢谢你
Thank you so much for today.
真是  真是太完美了
It was... it was perfect.
还没结束呢
It's not over yet.
上周到的
It arrived last week...
一位匿名人士捐赠的
from an anonymous donor.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你介意我们离开这倒霉窗户吗
Do you mind if we get the hell away from this window?
这是在等枪子儿
We're sitting ducks.
就是这个目的  德雷克先生
That's the point, Mr. Drake.
得让你们的杀手知道你们在家
Those hit men of yours need to know someone's home.
厨房很安全
Kitchen is secure.
莱奈尔  下次你约会的时候
You know, Lionel, next time you have a date,
别这么神神秘秘的
don't be so melodramatic.
我还以为你在谋划什么
I thought you might be up to something.
是啊  谋划个人私生活
Yeah, it's called a personal life.
屁股吃了一颗子弹
After taking a bullet in the ass
救了你也不止一次了
and saving yours more than once,
您认为我能有点隐私了吗
you think I've earned just a little privacy?
不能
No.
你确定他们会出现
You're sure they're even gonna show up?
这活儿得在明天之前搞定  对吗
You needed the job done by tomorrow, right?
是的
Yeah.
在董事会投票之前
Before the board votes?
是的
Yeah.
你们俩都没有支付全额
And neither of you paid the full amount?
没有
No.
很确定
Pretty sure.
我们要不要也带上枪
Should we get guns too?
我有更好的办法
I have a better idea.
等等
Wait.
-待着  -你要去哪儿
- Stay here. - Where are you going?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
拜托
Come on!
至少我们不会挨饿
Well, at least we won't get hungry.
神奇小子呢
Hey, where's Wonder Boy?
他在检查楼上
He's securing the upper levels,
以防圣地亚哥带同伴来
just in case Santiago brings company.
这么有钱  他们还是不快乐
All this money, and they're still unhappy.
丹尼尔  我们是怎么了
Oh, Daniel, what happened to us?
说实话  我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
那家伙说得对  我们不再交流了  不是吗
That guy was right about us not talking, wasn't he?
那事发生之后  你什么都不想谈了
You didn't want to discuss anything real after it happened.
我想再试一次  我问过你
I wanted us to try again. I asked you.
我也想再试试  但当时太急了
I wanted to try again too. It was just too soon.
然后你就说我应该休息一下
And then you said maybe I should take some time off,
好像都是我的错  因为我工作太卖命了
like it was my fault because I was working too hard.
我想让你待在家里
I wanted you to stay at home
是因为你刚经历了创伤  塞布丽娜
because you'd just been through a trauma, Sabrina,
不是责备你什么
not because I blamed you for anything.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
我的天啊  你原来是这么想的
Oh, my God. Is that what you thought?
难怪我总是无法亲近你
No wonder I couldn't reach you.
我还一直步步紧逼
And I kept pushing and pushing, and--
我  我不知道
I-I didn't know.
我从没明确说出来过  是吗
I never actually said it out loud, did I?
我埋头工作
I just threw myself into work
是因为这比面对那事要轻松
because that was easier than facing what had happened.
然后不知不觉  我拥有的就只剩公司了
And next thing I knew, the company was all I had left,
而你却想从我手中抢走
and you wanted to take it from me.
我得做个了结  我们之间
I had to be done... with us.
我一直都很愤怒
I mean, I am so angry all the time, and--
我了解那种感觉
I know the feeling.
我不想一无所有地离开
I mean, I didn't want to walk away with nothing.
毕竟我们经历了这么多
Not after everything we'd been through,
我成长的环境又是那样
not after the way I grew up.
我必须要卖掉它  即使
I needed to sell, even if--
英雄所见略同哈
Great minds think alike, huh?
丹尼  如果我们能摆脱
Danny, if we get out of this...
当  当我们摆脱
When. When we get out of here.
也许我们可以
Maybe we could--
从头再来会不会很疯狂
Too crazy if we try again?
我觉得我们已经够疯狂了
I think it's just crazy enough.
很抱歉我想杀死你  亲爱的
I'm so sorry I tried to kill you, honey.
我也是
Me too.
纽约警察
NYPD!
弗斯科
Fusco!
-不  -求你住手
- No! - Please, don't do this!
你躲不过去的  警探
You can't hide from me, Detective.
她才没躲
Hey, she ain't hiding.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
和快乐先生共事  我哪敢不穿防弹衣
I know better than to forget my vest when I'm working with Mr. Happy.
约翰呢
Where is John?
圣地亚哥呢
Santiago?
他和同伴已经被放倒了
He and his goons are down.
抱歉搞得很乱
Sorry about the mess.
没关系  反正我也不喜欢
It's okay. I didn't really like it anyway.
-行了吗  -好的
- You got it? - Yeah.
我会打电话给韦斯  他会帮我们找最好的律师
I'll call Wes. He'll get us the best lawyers.
咱们处理这事的时候  布鲁克斯会负责公司事务
Brooks will keep things going while we work this out.
他们又复合了  不是吧
They're back together? Come on.
爱情是很有趣的  弗斯科
Love's a funny thing, Fusco.
又一个凶案组的宁静夜晚啊
Just another quiet night on the task force, huh?
我得亲眼见证这派对
I had to see this party with my own eyes.
感谢援助  比彻
Thanks for the assist, Beecher.
要不是你  我可干不成
I couldn't have done it without you.
我不确定  看起来你自己也能搞定
I don't know about that. You seem like you can handle yourself.
即便如此  偶尔有人来帮忙真好
Even so, it's nice to have help now and then.
这样的话  卡尔・比彻乐意效劳  女士
If that's the case, Cal Beecher at your service, ma'am.
我还是欠你一次
I still owe you one.
通常我都会要一瓶烈点儿的酒
You know, normally, I'd ask for a bottle of something strong,
不过这次  晚餐怎么样
but, uh, what about dinner instead?
好
Okay.
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
? One of these mornings ?
? Won't be very long ?
卡特警探说德雷克夫妇今早被提审了
Detective Carter says the Drakes were arraigned this morning.
他们行使了配偶特权
They're invoking spousal privilege,
拒绝指证对方
refusing to testify against one another.
看来不离婚对他们来说终归是好的
Guess not getting divorced worked out for them after all.
他们会被判多久
Do you know how much time they'll get?
有他们的律师在  不会很久
With their lawyers? Probably very little.
闹了这么大一圈  最终发现自己还爱着对方
Lot of mayhem just to figure out they still loved each other.
我想一切都值得
I suppose anything is worthwhile
因为你有了第二次机会与爱人在一起
when life gives you a second chance to be with the one you love.
? One of these mornings ?
走吧  小熊
Come on, Bear.
? Won't be very long ?
? You will look for me ?
? And I'll be gone*
有什么心事  哈罗德
What's on your mind, Harold?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
拜托
Come on.
你有心事时总是这幅表情
You always get that look when something's on your mind.
是的吗
I do?
? And I'll be gone ?
格蕾丝  有些事你需要知道  关于我
Grace, there's something you should know about me
和  我的工作
and about... what I do.
哈罗德  不论你说什么
Harold, there's nothing you can say
我都不会离开
that will make me run away,
但你应该换个时间再说
But you should tell me in your own time,
换个你不是
when you don't have--
这种表情的时候
That look?
而且  我们的旅程刚刚开始
Besides, our journey starts here,
不论有什么待解的谜题
and any mystery around the corner...
我们都可以一起发掘
we can discover together.
? You will look for me ?
? And I'll be gone ?